你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
欢迎回来。
And welcome back.
我在上一个视频中给你留下了一些扣人心弦的东西，在那里你学习了所有关于管道的基础知识。
I left you with a bit of a cliffhanger in the last video where you learned all about the basics of piping.
现在，在这段视频中，我们将介绍您在上一段视频和
Now in this video we're going to take what you learned about the basics in the previous video and in
这个视频我们将把它升级，并教你一些先进的管道技术。
this video we're going to level it up and teach you some advanced piping techniques.
从昨晚的视频中学到的基本知识中，只需获取一条命令的输出即可
So with the basic stuff you learnt last night's video about just taking the output of one command and
通过管道将其直接输入到另一个的标准输入。
piping it directly into the input into the standard input of another.
这不会给灵活性留下太大的空间，而有很多非常酷的东西，你可以
That doesn't leave much room for flexibility whereas there's loads of really cool things that you can
如果你再多学几种技术，你的管道就不用了。
do with your pipelines if you learn just a few more techniques.
因此，在这段视频中，我们将回顾一下这些先进的管道技术。
So in this video we're going to go over those advanced piping techniques.
最后，您必须使用t和x ogg命令创建高级管道。
And by the end you have to make advanced pipelines using the t and x Ogg's commands.
所以，让我们继续往前跳，一头扎进去。
So let's go ahead and jump into it.
好的，让我们快速回顾一下我们在上一段视频中所做的。
All right so let's just have a quick recap of what we did in the last video.
因此，在上一个视频中，我们使用date命令来获取有关我们的计算机的大量系统信息
So in the last video we use the date command to get loads of system information about our computers
时钟，我们所做的是将数据传递给Cut命令，因为我们只想
clock and what we did was we passed that data into the cut command because we just wanted to cut out
一周中的某一天，也就是星期一。
the day of the week which is a Monday.
现在到了星期几，我们不得不说这个数据实际上被分成了几列
Now to the day of the week we have to say that this data is actually broken up into several columns
并且每列由空格隔开。
and each column is separated by a space.
现在，另一种说法是，每一列都由空格分隔，这在计算机中是一个花哨的词
Now another way of saying that is that each column is delimited by space that's a fancy word in computer
行话。
lingo.
所以我们做的就是给命令一个分隔符，我们说分隔符是一个空格。
And so what we did is we gave the the command a delimiter and we said the delimiter is a space.
好的。
OK.
现在，一旦我们说好了，每一列都被空格分开了。
And now once we've said OK Each column is split up by by spaces.
我们想要哪一栏？我们想要哪一栏？
Which field do we want which column do we want.
第一栏是什么？
What is the first column.
现在，CUT命令中的字段在COOK命令中称为可消除列，称为字段。
Now fields in the cut command are called effable columns in the cook commander called fields.
所以我们说Fields等于1，当我们按Enter键时，它将在周一中断。
So we said Fields equals 1 and when we pressed enter that cuts out Monday.
好的。
OK.
这就是我们在上一个视频中做的。
So that's what we did in the last video.
然后我给了你一个小小的挑战。
Then I gave you a little bit of a challenge.
我说，嘿，我们如何才能真正将这些信息保存到一个文件中。
I said hey how can we go about actually saving this information into a file.
但同时也将其向下传递到管道中。
But at the same time also pass it down into the pipeline.
那么，我们如何将其保存到文件中，同时又将其传递给厨师来吧，这样它就可以操作了
So how can we save it into a file but also pass it down into the cook come on so that it can be operated
这样我们周一就可以出去了。
on so we can get Monday out.
所以我们试图同时做两件事，所以要做到这一点，我们实际上需要另一个命令，名为
So we're trying to do two things at once so to do that we actually need to have another command called
命令。
the command.
那么让我们来看看这两个命令是如何工作的。
So let's take a look at how the two command works.
下面是TEE命令如何工作的图像。
So here's an image of how the tee command works.
现在在视频资源中放一个指向原始图片的链接。
Now put a link to the original picture in the video resources.
您可以在这里看到，我们在两个命令之间有一条管道，所以左边是一个命令。
You can see here that we have a pipe between two commands so here's a command over on the left.
我们在右边有另一个命令，在中间我们使用的是这个命令。
And we have another command over here on the right and in the middle we're using the command.
好的。
OK.
现在我们还没有讨论特定命令的作用。
Now we haven't covered what the specific commands do.
实际上这并不重要，我想要关注的是中间的T命令
It doesn't actually matter so much what I want to focus on is the T command in the middle and just on
我们正试图把两个命令连在一起。
that we're trying to pipe two commands together.
好的。
OK.
现在，就像水管中的T形接头一样，我们可以使用TEE命令使数据流入
Now just like a T-junction in a pipe of water we can use the tee command to cause our data to flow in
两个方向。
two directions.
我们可以让它水平流动，也可以垂直向下流动到你能想象到的文件中
We can cause it to flow horizontally as well as flow vertically downwards into the files you can imagine
它是这样工作的。
it working like that.
好的。
OK.
因此，团队指挥官允许我们将数据传递到管道的睡觉上。
So this the team commander allows us to pass the data on to the rest of the pipe.
但它也可以让我们把它保存在一个文件里。
But it also allows us to keep it in a file.
好的。
OK.
所以你可以在这里看到，我们在左边有一位指挥官，他正试图通过管道将其数据传送到
So you can see here that we've got a commander on the left that is trying to pipe its data across into
右边的另一个指挥员在中间，我们用管道通过TEE命令和命令
another commander on the right in the middle there we pipe it through the tee command and the command
我们给它一个命令行参数，一个DXi文件，可以是您想要的任何文件名。
we give it a command line argument a file that DXi that could be any file name that you want.
发生的情况是，数据确实会从一个命令的标准输出一直传递到
And what happens is the data does pass all the way through from the standard output of one command to
另一种是标准输入。
the standard input the other.
但它也会掉下来。
But it also falls down.
您可以想象它从您的命令行中掉落到一个名为FIELD或ATX的文件中
You can imagine it falling down from your command line it like into a file called filed or ATX or whatever
您为命令指定的文件名。
file name you gave the command.
这就是命令的工作方式。
So that's how the command works.
从理论上讲，这就是这个图形的工作方式，让我们继续下去，看看它在实践中是如何工作的。
In theory this is how this graphic works and let's go ahead and see it work in practice.
好的，你永远不会明白t命令是如何工作的，我只是快速刷新了一下我们的命令流水线。
OK so never you understand how the t command works I just have a quick refresher of our command pipeline.
我们有DATE命令，它为我们提供关于系统时钟的一大堆信息，我们
We have the date command which gives us a whole bunch of information about our systems clock and we
我想把周一或者一周中的任何一天都删掉，其实还可以。
wanted to cut out the Monday or whatever day of the week it actually is OK.
因此，我们采用DATE命令，并将其转换为CUT命令。
So we take the date command and we piped it into the cut command.
现在我们注意到，数据被分成用空格分隔的列。
Now we notice that the data is broken up into columns that are separated by spaces.
所以我们说，嘿，拜托，我们有一个分隔符，那是一个空格，数据是由空格分隔的，我们想要
So we say hey come on we have a delimiter that's a space the data is delimited by spaces and we want
第一列或如命令所称的第一个字段，它为我们提供了一周中的第几天，
the first column or as the command calls it the first field and that gives us the day of the week which
在这种情况下是星期一。
in this case is Monday.
现在的挑战是，我们不仅要让它出来，我们还想保存整个日期AK
Now the challenge was we want to not only have that come out we also want to save the entire date AK
到一个名为Full Dotti XTi的文件中。
into a file called called full date Dotti XTi.
好的。
OK.
这就是我们将如何做到这一点。
So here's how we would do that.
然后按下镶木地板就可以到达我们之前的位置。
And then press the paroquet to get where we got before.
现在我要做的就是把命令塞进去。
Now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to squeeze in here the command.
好的。
OK.
现在，该命令将把像T-JOINT这样的一个放入我们的管道中。
Now the command is going to put one of those like T-junction in our pipeline.
你需要在你的脑海中想象它。
You need to imagine it in your head.
好的。
OK.
所以接下来会发生的是，数据将会一直水平地通过管道。
So what's going to happen is the data is going to pass all the way through the pipeline horizontally.
所以它将从日期开始传递到标准输出，然后进入杯子的标准输入
So it's going to pass from the date come on standard output and go into the standard input of the cup
赶快。
come on.
所以它会径直流过。
So it's going to flow straight the way through.
但是tee命令要做的是，它将允许我们垂直向下保存数据
But what the tee command is going to do is it's going to allow us to save the data vertically downwards
所以你可以看到它像一个大字母T，A，K，像一个大的T形交叉口。
so you can watch it being like a big letter T A K like a big T-junction.
日期将向下放入名为Full Date的文件中。
The date is going to go downwards into the file called full date.
XTi医生好的。
Dr. XTi Okay.
所以我们今天在这里，我们将横向向下操作，内部也不会有任何关于这一点的讨论
So here we are today is going to go horizontal down ops either no internal about that is going to go
横向横跨。
horizontally across.
好的。
OK.
它还将垂直向下放入一个名为全天的文件中。
And it's also going to go vertically downwards into a file called full day.
XTi博士，因为当我们这样做时，我们看到一周中某一天的输出仍然发生，因为
Dr. XTi because when we do that we see that the output of the day of the week is still happened because
那是穿过伤口的，来吧。
that was passed through the cut Come on.
快点，把它吐到它的标准输出端，这个输出端还连接着我们的终端。
Come on spit it out to its standard output which is still connected to our terminal.
当我们打开我们的文件资源管理器时，我们可以看到这一点。
Boom we open up our file explorer we can see that.
现在我们有一个名为Full Date的文件。
Now we have a file called full date.
博士。
Dr..
我删除了我们之前拥有的所有其他信息。
I deleted all of the other ones we have before.
所以我们重新开始，现在我们有了完整日期的DirectX磁带。
So we were starting afresh and now we have full date directx tape.
当我打开那个井的时候，嘿，我们实际上可以看到所有的数据数据确实已经保存在
And when I open that well hey we can actually see that all of the data data has been indeed saved in
一个名为Full Date的文件。
a file called full date.
多蒂·西蒂没那么厉害。
Dottie XTi Isn't that awesome.
这很合适。
That's proper.
好的，所发生的是DATE命令SPACE所有的信息
All right so what happened was the date command spatio all of its information all the way across the
管道，当它到达TQM上的茶杯时，我只是对管道中的数据进行了快照
pipeline and when it got to the teacup on the TQM I just took a snapshot of the data in the pipeline
并将其传递到一个名为Full Date的文件中。
and passed it down into a file called full date.
XTi博士，因此该文件包含DATE命令输出的所有数据。
Dr. XTi so that file contains all of the data that's coming out the date command.
好的，但是随后数据被传递到Cut命令中，该命令进行一些处理，并将空间
OK but then the data was passed on into the cut command which did some processing and that spatio the
一周中的哪一天，在这种情况下是星期一。
day of the week which in this case was Monday.
不，我有个快速挑战要给你，好吗？
No I've got a quick challenge for you OK.
我想你可以做到的。
And I think you can do it.
我们该怎么办。
What are we to do.
我想让你看看你能不能做到，而不是把一周中的某一天都吐到航站楼
I want you to instead of having the day the week spit out to the terminal I want you to see if you can
了解如何使用重定向将数据实际保存到名为Today的文件中
figure out how you can use redirection to actually cause that data to be saved in a file called today
西蒂医生。
Dr. XTi.
好的。
OK.
因此，与其让SpinSpotter去商店，不如去航站楼。
So instead of having the day of the week SpinSpotter to the shop bespattered to the terminal.
我想让你把它保存在一个叫今天XTi博士的文件里，但是你还需要有命令
I want you to have it saved in a file called today Dr. XTi But also you still need to have the command
他必须按下OK才能获得您以前拥有的内容，然后现在进行重定向。
in he has to press the OK to get what you've got before and now do the redirection.
好的。
OK.
所以我现在要把视频拉出来，然后回来看看你做得怎么样
So I'm going to pull the video now and then come back and see how you did
你是怎么做到的。
How'd you manage it.
是你做的吗。
Did you do it.
嗯，这就是你，这就是我要做的。
Well this is how you this is how I'd go about it.
正确的。
Right.
所以我就写在这里的末尾，因为这是数据的实际来源。
So I would just write at the end here because here's where the data is actually coming out from.
我只需要将标准输出重定向到一个名为TODAY的文件。
I would just have a redirection from standard output into a file called today.
XTI，从字面上看就是这么简单。
XTi and it's literally just that simple.
好的。
OK.
一旦我们这样做了，如果我继续按Enter，我们可以看到，当我们打开我们的文件指挥官
So once we've done that if I go ahead and press ENTER we can see that when we open up our file commander
这里我们还有一个文件，叫做今天的XTi博士。
here we've also got a file called today Dr. XTi.
在那里，它保存了一周中的那一天的数据，在本例中是星期一。
And inside there it has saved the data that day of the week which in this case was Monday.
让我删除这两个文件，这样我们就可以看到这一切的辉煌。
Let me delete both files so we can see this in all its glory.
我没有文件，按Parakey，然后按Enter。
I've got no files and press the Parakey press enter.
当我们看一看时，我们实际上已经设法将所有数据保存到全职医生60中，我们已经
And when we take a look we've actually managed to save all the data into full date doctor 60 and we've
还设法将我们想要的内容通过重定向保存到今天的DirectX。
also managed to save just what we wanted using redirection into today directx.
这不是很棒吗。
Isn't that awesome.
对，那是一种。
Right that's kind of.
那真是太棒了。
That's really awesome.
不管怎样，我们在这里看到的是T命令基本上是对流动的数据进行快照
So anyway so what we've got here is the T command basically takes a snapshot of the data that's flowing
在该点上通过管道，并将其保存在您提供的文件中。
through the pipe at that point and saves it in a file that you give it.
好的。
OK.
然后重定向也会做同样的事情。
And then redirection will also do the same.
但是，一旦您重定向了标准输出，您就不能再将其传递到管道中。
But once you've redirected standard output you can no longer pass it down the pipe.
好的，这就是我们使用T命令的原因，该命令允许标准输出继续向下流动
OK so that's why we use the T command the command allows standard output to continue flowing down the
管道，而且还允许您有效地将其重定向到文件并拍摄快照，以便将其保存
pipe but also allows you to effectively redirect it to a file and take a snapshot so that it's saved
那里。
there.
换句话说，一旦你做了重定向，你就不能再做管道了。
So another way of saying that is that once you've done redirection you can't do any more piping.
好的，一旦您重定向了标准输出，就像我们在今天文本中所做的那样。
OK so once you've redirected standard output like we have here in the today text.
好的，我们不能再做比管道更多的管道了，我要把码头最大化。
Ok we can no longer do any more piping down than a pipe I'm going to maximize the terminal we can.
一旦我们完成了到0.60的重定向，我们的管道时代就结束了。
Once we've done this redirection to 0.60 that's the end of our piping days.
但是，如果我们想要保存今天的所有数据，那么我们可以做些什么呢？这需要继续这条管道。
But what we could do if we wanted to save all the data in today that takes to continue the pipeline.
然后呢。
Then what.
那就是T命令进来的时候。
Then that's when the T command would come in.
好的，举个例子，我们今天停靠在这里的茶量，现在我们可以继续管道。
OK so we do for example today docked here in the Teac amount and now we can continue to pipe.
好吧。
Okay.
所以再说一遍，如果您重定向jackalope，这意味着如果您想要拍摄快照，就不会再有管道
So just again if you do redirection of jackalope that means no more piping if you want to take a snapshot
但是继续管子，那是你用茶量的时候，现在我可以继续往下管子了。
but continue piping that's when you use the Teac amount and now I could continue piping on down.
好吧。
Okay.
所以我想在这段视频中也介绍X Ogg的命令，但我认为我们在这里是在拖延时间。
So I wanted to also cover the X Ogg's commands in this video but I think we're pushing it for time here.
我希望这已经清楚地说明了发球台的命令是什么，在这里对球队和
I hope that that has made it clear what the tee command is in final summary here for the team and the
Team命令允许您保存数据的快照并继续执行管道操作，而仅使用
team command allows you to save a snapshot of the data and continue doing your piping whereas just using
重定向将保存数据的快照。
redirection will save a snapshot of the data.
但是你不能再做任何管道了。
But you can no longer do any piping.
因此，如果您希望继续构建管道，但要保留数据的快照，请使用T命令。
So if you want to keep building your pipeline but keep a snapshot of the data use the T command instead.
所以在下一个视频中我们要做的是看看X Ogg的命令
So in the next video what we're going to do is we're going to have a look at the X Ogg's command which
是一个非常强大的命令，它允许您将管道数据转换为命令行参数。
is a really powerful command that allows you to turn your pipes data into command line arguments.
好的，那么让我们继续，我将在下一个视频中看到那里。
OK so let's go ahead and I'll see the there in the next video.